NATHAN HEMESATH

1725 Coronita Dr, Fenton, MO 63026

hemesath2@gmail.com (319) 429-4274

PERSONAL STATEMENT

First and foremost, I am a self-starter. Learning new coding languages and techniques is exciting. Through my variety of work experience, I've had the opportunity to discover that my passion lies in a field where I can work with a team to create a unique, exciting product for the client. I have the passion, motivation, and work ethic to be a great addition to a similarly motivated team.

EXPERIENCE

User Interface Web Developer, VGM Forbin

(Jan 2016 – Present)

- Translate the design team's vision for the website into code
- Create sites for a variety of industries (Medical, Banking, Restaurant, etc)
- Main coding languages/skills: HTML, CSS, JQuery, SASS/SCSS, custom animation
- Also familiar with PHP and .NET for daily tasks and debugging
- Conducted research and collaborated as part of the newly formed applications team in the early stages of future app development for the company (Languages: Swift 2, Angular JS, Node JS, and Firebase)

Intern in Web Developing, Connell Aviation Group

(Aug 2015 – Nov 2015)

- Maintained multiple Wordpress site's
- Repaired previously built sites to improve functionality for the client.

Electro-Medical Patient Care Coordinator, VGM Group

(2014 – Dec 2016)

- "Conveyed important information between insurance companies and their clients to ensure providers could supply them with much needed supplies"
- "Assisted patients in need of TENS/NMES units to help relieve pain and live a normal life"
- "Exceeded production goals which allowed insurance adjusters to lighten their workload"

Warehouse Worker, Target Food Distribution

(2011-2013)

- Organized a team of warehouse employees to efficiently perform daily tasks
- Trained and directed new team members
- Volunteered and contributed as part of the General Safety Team, addressing crucial risks and precautions

EDUCATION

Associates in Web Programming and Development Hawkeye Community College, Waterloo, IA Graduated 2016

Bachelors of Science – Criminology *University of Northern Iowa*, Cedar Falls, IA

Graduated 2011